Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Able to handle any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 1 year of related experience. I hope to work as a Full-stack Developer

Work History

2019-09 -2019-12

Front End Developer Intern

HNG Internship 6.0, Benin, Edo

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS, including Bootstrap integration and cross-browser compatibility, to support marketing.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices.
- Helped in developing 2 web applications alongside other Software developers

2017-09 -2018-07

IT Consultant

Edo State House Of Assembly, Benin, Edo

- Adjusted software parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.
- Inspected equipment, assessed functionality and optimized controls.
- Walked clients and internal staff through troubleshooting steps to resolve common software issues.

EGHE EHIOROBO

Software Developer

Contact

Address

No 6, Ogba Market Road Benin, Edo, 300271

Phone

081-089-41874

E-mail

ehioroboeghe@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedln.com/in/eghe-ehiorobo

Skills

CSS proficiency

JavaScript Proficiency

HTML expertise

Troubleshooting and debugging

API design knowledge

Programming

React.js

Node.js

PostgreSQL

PHP Knowledge

Bootstrap proficiency

Github

 Translated technical concepts and information into terms all parties could easily comprehend.

Assisted 8 reporters with IT related issues within 10 months

2014-02 -2014-08

IT Intern

Integrated Data Service Limited, ACSD, Benin, Edo

- Identified management control weaknesses and provided value added suggestions for remediation.
- Evaluated design and operating effectiveness of audit areas, including efficiency, effectiveness, and mitigating controls.
- Followed quality standards and procedures to minimize errors and maximize customer satisfaction.
- Managed logistics operations to meet customer expectations and financial standards and policies.
- Identified and resolved process issues to encourage smoother procedures, more efficient workflow and overall business growth.
- Helped with solving IT related problems in approximately 3 different departments
- Performed Preventive and Corrective Maintenance
- Installation of new Computer Systems, Anti-Virus and other Utility Software
- Undertaking significant amount of client Mac Address for Inventory purpose
- Ensuring all Systems were Fit and meeting staff needs

Education

2012-08 -

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

2016-07

Benson Idahosa University - Benin City

2003-09 -

Some College (No Degree)

2009-07

Greater Tomorrow Secondary School - Benin City

Certifications

2019-12

The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery via Udemy

Problem Solving

Express

Knex.js